<?xml version="1.0"?>
<world>
  <places>

    <place id="0">
      <name>Beach</name>
      <description>You look around and see a bunch of equipment stuff laying on the ground.</description>
        <item>
          <name>Machete</name>
          <description>This is a sharp meele weapon which can also be used to cut plants.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Flashlight</name>
        <description>The battery is on low charge but a small light is better than no light.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rope</name>
        <description>This is a long rope which has an iron hook at the end which can be used to climb.</description>
        </item>
    </place>
    <place id="1">
      <name>Coast</name>
      <description>You enter a barren Coast which borders on a deep Jungle.</description>
      <item>
        <name>Cloth</name>
        <description>This is a part of a cloth which can be used as a bandage or to clean yourself or something else.</description>
      </item>
    </place>
    <place id="2">
      <name>Jungle</name>
      <description>You got lost in the downs of the deep Jungle. You can't orientate yourself.</description>
      <item>
        <name>Plank</name>
        <description>This is a wooden plank which lied in the water at the beach.</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <name>Stone</name>
        <description>This is a sharp stone.</description>
      </item>
    </place>
    <place id="3">
      <name>Cave</name>
      <description>You enter a dark cave. You can hear a drumming noise from the deeper inside.</description>
      <item>
        <name>Compass</name>
        <description>The needle always sign to north. Now you can orientate yourself in the jungle.</description>
      </item>
    </place>
    <place id="4">
      <name>Outback</name>
      <description>After you followed the signed path, you enter the jungle's outback, which is less deep as the upper lands.</description>
      <item>
        <name>Signal Rocket</name>
        <description>There is one missile left which can be used to call someones attention.</description>
      </item>
    </place>
    <place id="5">
      <name>Beach at the other side</name>
      <description>You found a way out of the jungle and enter the beach at the other side of the island. In the distance you can see the silhouette of a ship.</description>
    </place>
    <place id="6">
      <name>Ship of Coastguard</name>
      <description>You are saved by the coastguard. Just in the moment you feel saved and rescued, you realize that it is not the coastguard but pirates who seem to use you as their new slave.</description>
    </place>
    <place id="7">
      <name>Bad Ending</name>
      <description>The wood is old and rotten. It instantly breaks after you tried to walk on it and you fall to death.</description>
    </place>
    <place id="8">
      <name>Another Bad Ending</name>
      <description>After you fired your Signal Rocket, you are hit by arrows. An unfriendly civilization of Indians found another human meal.</description>
    </place>

  </places>

  <passages>

    <passage>
      <name>High Cliff</name>
      <description>This is a very sharp and high cliff. You need something to climb it.</description>
      <obstacle>
        <description>You need to find a way to climb the cliff.</description>
        <resolution>You used the rope to climb the cliff.</resolution>
        <requiredItem>2</requiredItem>
      </obstacle>
      <entrancePlace>0</entrancePlace>
      <exitPlace>1</exitPlace>
    </passage>


  </passages>

</world>
